shutterflyinc.com 2019-12-21

# Shutterfly, Inc. Online Privacy and Security | Shutterfly, Inc

Last Updated: September 3, 2019

Shutterfly, Inc. and our family of brands take your privacy seriously. Please read the following to learn more about our privacy policy.

Our Online Privacy and Security is organized as follows:

  1. Information Collected
  2. Cookies and Similar Technologies
  3. Authorized Third Parties
  4. Use of Information
  5. Information Sharing With Third Parties
  6. Children’s Information
  7. Access to Your Account Information and Preferences
  8. Confidentiality and Security
  9. Third Party Sites
  10. Your California Privacy Rights
  11. Questions and Suggestions
  12. Updates to Privacy Policy

## 1\. Information Collected

We collect personal information when you register with any of our family of brands via our websites, mobile sites or mobile applications (collectively, our “Sites and Apps”) when you use any of our products or services and when you complete a survey or enter a contest or sweepstakes that we sponsor. Personal information is any information about you that is personally identifiable, such as your name, address, email address or phone number, and any other information that is not otherwise publicly available.

In addition, if you send email invitations to friends and family to allow them to view your pictures or saved projects, or if you invite them to participate in Shutterfly Share Sites, those email addresses are personal information.

Also, your account includes an address book, which you can use to store email addresses of friends and family, and those emails are personal information.

We or our third party service providers may also collect information relating to your devices, including your device model, operating system, browser type, unique device identifier, IP address, mobile phone number, mobile network carrier, location, and event information (such as application installations).

If you order products or pay for services, we will need your shipping address, billing name and address, as well as your credit card number and expiration date.

When you upload your photos to our platform or give us permission to access the photos stored on your device, your photo content may also include related image information such as the time and the place your photo was taken and similar “metadata” captured by your image capture device.

If you log into your Shutterfly account through a social media site, we will have access to certain information from that site, such as your name, account information and profile photo, in accordance with the authorization procedures determined by such social media site.

## 2\. Cookies and Similar Technologies

We use cookies, pixel tags, and/or other similar technologies to collect visitor information.

Cookies, for example, are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser. They make it possible for us to store the contents of your shopping cart until you are ready to check out, recognize your browser when you visit and provide you with information about products that interest you. By doing this, we can personalize your return visits and save you time during checkout. It is possible to prevent cookies from being used in your browser by turning the feature off, but in order to enjoy the benefits of being a registered user, your browser must be set to accept cookies.

## 3\. Authorized Third Parties

We may share your personal information with third parties who provide support services to us, such as helping us deliver communications, fulfill customer orders, enhance and personalize your shopping experience with us, process credit card orders and the like. If so, these parties are authorized to use the personal information solely in conjunction with the specific service they provide to or on behalf of Shutterfly.

We use third-party service providers to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet and sometimes on our Sites and Apps. They may collect anonymous information about your visits to our Sites and Apps and your interaction with our products and services. They may also use information about your visits to our Sites and Apps and other sites and mobile applications to target ads for products and services. For instance, they may collect web log data from you (such as IP address and information about your browser or operating system) or place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser to enable you to receive customized ads. Through this process, demographic or other interest data may be associated with your browser or device in a non-personally identifiable manner.

The NAI (Network Advertising Initiative) allows for the central opting out of all of its members’ cookies from a single opt-out page. If you prefer not to receive relevant advertising on web pages, please click on the following link: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>. If you delete your cookies, use a different browser or buy a new computer, you will need to renew your opt-out choice.

We also work with third party service providers to monitor certain pages of our Sites and Apps for such purposes as reporting traffic and other advertising statistics. Where authorized by us, these third party providers may use cookies and/or other monitoring technologies to compile anonymous statistics about our visitors.

We may also allow third parties to provide us with analytics about your visits to our Sites and Apps. The third party analytics services may use cookies, web beacons and other technologies to collect information about your use of the Sites and Apps and other websites, including your IP address, web browser, pages viewed, time spent on pages, and links clicked. This information may be used to, among other things, analyze and track data, improve our service, determine the popularity of certain content and better understand our users’ online activity.

## 4\. Use of Information

We use your information for the following general purposes: to fulfill your requests for products and services, administrative purposes, to improve our services, to customize the advertising and content you see, to offer suggestions for personalized products based on your content,  to contact you, and for internal business purposes.

We use third party information you provide to us solely to provide services you specifically request. For example, sharing your pictures electronically is one of the key benefits we offer. You are able to send an email invitation to your selected recipients, and then to allow them to view, save, or purchase products from your pictures. This email invitation contains a link created specifically for your pictures. The email also may include information about special promotional offers from our family of brands and/or carefully-screened third parties.

Another example of how we use third party information you provide to us is Shutterfly Share Sites. If you create a special site through Shutterfly Share Sites to share your pictures, you may invite recipients to participate in that site. In addition to the email invitation, these recipients will receive notifications in the form of email digests as changes are made to the site (e.g., when new content is added). As the creator of the site, you can determine the frequency of these email digests. In addition, any recipient who is a Shutterfly member can change how often he or she wishes to receive these digests through his or her account preferences.

If you use one of our referral programs to refer any of our family of brands to your friends and family, we will use their email addresses to send your invitation.

Please be assured that we do not use the email addresses that you enter through email invitations, Shutterfly Share Sites, our referrals programs, or the address books of any of our Sites and Apps to send any type of direct marketing to your friends and family. (Of course, if a friend or family member signs up with any of our family of brands or we receive their email address from another unrelated source, we may communicate with them in accordance with this Privacy Policy.)

Your accounts may also contain a calendar where you can store birthdays, anniversaries, and other key dates and details about friends and family. You can use this information to help keep in touch with friends and family on important dates. We may send you email reminders of the personalized dates you have entered in this calendar. Reminder information is highly confidential and will not be shared with any third parties.

When you upload your photos to our platform or give us permission to access the photos stored on your device, we may analyze your photo content and metadata to help you tag and organize your photos and to make personalized product suggestions to you based on those photos, such as showing you how your pictures may look in a collage or other Shutterfly product.  As you add new photos, we automatically associate similar faces, places and other image characteristics within your photo collection.  We only use this feature to help you organize, tag and create personalized products from your own photos. We never attempt to determine whether any similar faces appear in photos uploaded by different Shutterfly users or otherwise identify the people in your photos.  We do not sell or share this information with other third parties.  And we won’t suggest any tags for your own photos except the ones that you choose to create for your own face groups.

We use anonymous information, such as that pertaining to web or mobile pages you have viewed, in order to analyze trends, track user’s movements, provide a better user experience and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. We may also combine this with other customer information to improve our services and to customize the advertising and content you see.  See “Authorized Third Parties.”

As we continue to develop our business, we may undergo a business transition such as acquiring another company, merging with an existing company, or selling all or a portion of our assets. In such transitions, customer information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. In the event that we or substantially all of our assets are acquired or enter a court proceeding, you acknowledge that such transfers may occur and that your personal information can continue to be used as set forth in this privacy policy.

## 5\. Information Sharing With Third Parties

From time to time we share the personal information we collect with trusted companies who work with or on behalf of us. We may share personal information within our family of brands. We may also combine personal information with publicly available information and information we receive from or cross-reference with our partners. These companies may use your personal information to enhance and personalize your shopping experience with us, to communicate with you about products and events that may be of interest to you and for other promotional purposes. Information sharing allows us to introduce new resources based on your interests and needs. With that in mind, when you purchase an item, your customer information may be shared with other select companies whose products and services you may find useful and those select companies will handle, store, retain, use, share and access personal information in accordance with their own privacy policies, and we disclaim any and all liability relating thereto.

## 6\. Children’s Information

Our Sites and Apps are not intended for children, and we will not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children. If we become aware that a subscriber is under the age of 13, we will remove their personally identifiable information from our files.

## 7\. Access to Your Account Information and Preferences

You have the right and ability to edit your member account information on our Sites and Apps at any time. You can opt in or out of receiving future communications from us about special offers and new product information, you can unsubscribe by following instructions contained in the messages you receive, or you can change your marketing preferences by contacting us through the Contact Us page of any of our brands. We do reserve the right to send you certain communications relating to the services we provide, such as service announcements and administrative messages. We do not offer you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving those communications.

California’s “Do Not Track” Notice: “Do Not Track” (“DNT”) is a preference you can set in your web browser to let the sites you visit know that you do not want them collecting information about you. Our sites do not currently respond to “Do Not Track” settings. For further details regarding DNT, visit donottrack.us.

## 8\. Confidentiality and Security

We use a secure server (SSL) to encrypt your personal financial information. We use other physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect the security and confidentiality of the information we have collected, and to prevent unauthorized access to or disclosure of your information.

## 9\. Third Party Sites

Our Sites and Apps may contain links to other sites for news and other information. Our Privacy Policy only applies to our Sites and Apps, and we are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other sites which are linked to or integrated with our Sites and Apps. You should check the privacy policies of those sites before providing your personal information to them. See our Terms of Use for additional information.

## 10\. Your California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as S.B. 27, allows individual customers who have provided their personal information to us to request information about our disclosure of certain categories of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. Such requests must be submitted to us in one of the following ways: send a letter to Legal, Shutterfly, 2800 Bridge Parkway Redwood City, CA 94065 or through the various ways of contact described in the Contact Us page of any of our brands. Within thirty days of receiving such a request, we will provide a list of the categories of personal information disclosed to third parties for third party direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding year, along with the names and addresses of those third parties. This request may be made no more than once per calendar year. We reserve the right not to respond to requests submitted in ways other than those specified above.

## 11\. Questions and Suggestions

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, you can contact us through the [Contact Us](https://www.shutterflyinc.com/contact/) page of any of our brands, by writing to us at Privacy Office, Shutterfly, Inc., 2800 Bridge Pkwy, Redwood City, CA 94065, or by email to privacy@shutterfly.com..

## 12\. Updates to Privacy Policy

We may modify this Privacy Policy from time to time by posting updates on this page. Please check back periodically to view any updates.
